Deception never looked so sweet
Snow White is a adventure, fantasy, tv movie film directed by Caroline Thompson.
Snow White's mother dies during childbirth, leaving baby Snow and father John for dead on an icy field,
who then receives a visit from one of Satan's representatives, granting him three wishes.
Elspeth, played by Miranda Richardson.
John, played by Tom Irwin.
Josephine, played by Vera Farmiga.
Snow White, played by Kristin Kreuk.
The Granter of Wishes, played by Clancy Brown.
Wednesday, played by Vincent Schiavelli.
Snow White: The Fairest of Them All  is a 2001 fantasy adventure television film co-written
and directed by Caroline Thompson and produced by Hallmark Entertainment.
The film was first released theatrically in Europe, and subsequently aired in the United States on
ABC as part of their series on The Wonderful World of Disney on March 17, 2002.
Based upon the traditional Snow White folktale first recorded in 1812 by German folklorists the Brothers
Grimm, the film deviates from earlier interpretations of the story in several respects.
Set in a fantasy kingdom, it tells the story of Snow White (Kristin Kreuk), and the attempts of
her malevolent stepmother, Queen Elspeth (Miranda Richardson), to eliminate her.
Trying to escape Queen Elspeth's machinations, Snow White flees to
the forest, where she befriends Sunday (Michael J.
Anderson), the leader of the seven dwarfs, and
together they plot the monarch's overthrow.
Reviews were mixed, with Richardson's performance receiving praise,
but Kreuk's coming under criticism for being too bland.
The film would subsequently be released on DVD.
The film explores themes of stepmother, evil witch, woman director.